getrichslowly.org 2018-10-31

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use

**Your privacy is important to us.** Where user privacy is concerned, we at Get Rich Slowly follow a few fundamental principles:

  * We don't share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop products, or protect our rights.
  * We do not sell user information.
  * We don't store personal information on our host's servers unless required for the ongoing operation of this website or one of its services.

In the blog and its products, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what's visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted. **You can contact us any time via[the contact form](https://www.getrichslowly.org/contact/) if you have any questions about the site or its policies.**

GetRichSlowly.org officially operates under a small company called Computer Resources Northwest LLC, which will hereafter in this document be referred to as “CompResNW.” It is CompResNW's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information it may collect while operating this website and other websites that operate under CompResNW.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, CompResNW collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. CompResNW's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how CompResNW visitors use its websites. From time to time, CompResNW may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, for example by publishing a post on trends in the usage of its websites.

CompResNW also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments. CompResNW only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrator of the site where the comment was left. (In normal operations, we never look at this info. The only time we've ever used it is to block recurring spammers and hostile trolls.)

CompResNW may make use of third-party services that access personal information including but not limited to email addresses, IP addresses and other non-personally identifying information. CompResNW cannot oversee or be held liable for third party usage of such information.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to CompResNW's websites choose to interact with CompResNW in ways that require CompResNW to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that CompResNW gathers depends on the nature of the interaction.

Those who engage in transactions with CompResNW – by purchasing products or services, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, CompResNW collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with CompResNW. CompResNW does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection Act

COPPA is a U.S. law that restricts how websites can collect information about children. According to the FTC, “The Rule applies to operators of commercial websites and online services directed to children under 13 that collect, use, or disclose personal information from children, and operators of general audience websites or online services with actual knowledge that they are collecting, using, or disclosing personal information from children under 13.”

CompResNW does not operate websites directed to children under 13 and does not collect, use or disclose personal information from visitors known to be under 13.

### Aggregated Statistics

CompResNW may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, CompResNW may monitor inbound traffic sources, visitor time spent online, bounce rate, and so on. CompResNW may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, CompResNW does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

CompResNW discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that:

  * (i) need to know that information in order to process it on CompResNW's behalf or to provide services available at CompResNW's websites, and
  * (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using CompResNW's websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

CompResNW will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, CompResNW discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when CompResNW believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of CompResNW, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a subscriber of a CompResNW website and have supplied your email address, CompResNW may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with CompResNW and our products. We generally use articles on our websites to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum.

CompResNW takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns.

CompResNW uses cookies to help it identify and track visitors, their usage of CompResNW websites, and their website access preferences. CompResNW visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using CompResNW's websites, with the drawback that certain features of CompResNW's websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Business Transfers

If CompResNW, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that CompResNW goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of CompResNW may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

For instance, when J.D. Roth (and his company Computer Resources Northwest LLC) [sold GetRichSlowly.org to Quinstreet](https://www.getrichslowly.org/how-and-why-i-sold-get-rich-slowly/) in April 2009, Quinstreet acquired existing user information. When J.D. [re-purchased the site in October 2018](https://www.getrichslowly.org/i-bought-get-rich-slowly/), he re-acquired that user information.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by CompResNW and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

For more info, read our advertising disclosure to learn [how Get Rich Slowly makes money](https://www.getrichslowly.org/advertising-disclosure/).

### Comments

Comments contributed by visitors to CompResNW's websites, including all information supplied in the comment form including Name (as supplied by the visitor) and Website are visible to all other visitors and are stored on the server indefinitely.

An email address is also necessary to leave a comment and is stored by the blogging software but it is not visible to visitors. It is not required to be a valid email address, and will never be given away or sold or added to mailing lists without permission, or used for any reason except for the administrator to contact the commenting visitor.

This seldom happens and usually only happens when you are a regular commente we believe you would actually want to hear from me, and we don't have a better way of contacting you. (For example, if we wanted to ask a question about the book you recommended in your comment.)

Still, CompResNW reserves the right to do so for any reason.

### Correspondence sent via contact form

GetRichSlowly.org has a [contact form](https://www.getrichslowly.org/contact/) that website visitors may use to get in touch with us. Plus, it's not exactly tough to guess J.D.'s email address. This content may be published on the blog, with personally-identifying information removed. We will almost always ask permission before doing so, but reserve the right to publish non-personally-identifying content copied from inbound contact form emails without the user's permission, in the event that we believe it has value to other visitors of CompResNW's websites.

If the visitor requests beforehand that it not be published, or expressly denies permission beforehand when asked, it will not be published.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, CompResNW may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in CompResNW's sole discretion. CompResNW encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

This Privacy Policy was adapted from that of [Automattic.com](https://automattic.com/) via Creative Commons Sharealike license. You are free to use it too, as long as you offer your resulting policy under Creative Commons Sharealike license, and maybe link to Automattic.com because it was cool of them to offer it for others to use it as a framework.

### General Disclaimer

All content provided on this site is for informational purposes only. Please note that GetRichSlowly.org and its parent company Computer Resources Northwest LLC has financial relationships with some of the merchants and website proprietors mentioned on this blog.

However, **we do not engage in disingenuous endorsement**. If we say we like something, we really do. If we say something is worthwhile, we really think it is.

Get Rich Slowly makes no guarantees as to accuracy, completeness, or relevance of any claims made on this site and will not be held liable for any errors or omissions in their content, or any losses, injuries, damages or misunderstandings arising from the publication or use of this site's content.

All information and advice is the opinion of the giver, whether it is that of the proprietor of the site or that of a visitor. Do with it what you will and take responsibility for it.

***

Computer Resources Northwest LLC  
21105 S Wisteria Road  
West Linn, Oregon 97068
